# Leon Meyer

whoisleonmeyer@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/leon-meyer Zietenstraße 99, Düsseldorf, Germany, 40225

### **Summary**

Passionate & seasoned full-stack developer with over 9 years of experience developing a number of progressive web applications of diverse industries. Quickly helps small startups and enterprises with prototypes and ideas by efficiently implementing these into reality. My major tech stack is JavaScript and its based frameworks like React, Vue.js and Node.js as well as other languages like TypeScript, PHP and Python.

### **Education**

Vienna University of Technology

Mar 2009 - Apr 2014

Major: Computer Science, Bachelor's Degree (GPA: 3.5)

Minor: Electrical Engineering

## **Experience**

## ResultID (US, Remote) Senior Front-End Engineer

Oct 2020 - Present

- Built an Al-Driven platform to summarize market data using React, React Native, Next.js, Vue.js
   TypeScript, Node.js and PostgreSQL.
- Lead the front-end team, collaborated with the PM to achieve business objectives in the application.
- Took full ownership of the admin portal of the application built using React, Next.js, Python, FastAPI.
- Implemented micro-frontend pattern and managed collection of sample components using Storybook.
- Integrated **GraphQL** & **RESTful** APIs to the front-end application.
- Integrated 3rd party libraries like **OAuth**, **Mixpanel** and **Chart.js**.
- Worked directly with the design team to translate Figma design into pixel-perfect and responsive pages.
- Strongly experienced in daily peer code review and feature review on the product road map.
- Conducted automation testing using **Jest**, **React Testing Library**, **Cypress** and increased test coverage up to 50%.
- Used skills: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, React, React Native, Next.js, Vue.js, Node.js, FastAPI, Storybook, OAuth, Chart.js, Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS, Jira, Slack, Git.

#### **Outrider**

Nov 2017 - Sept 2020

#### **Full-Stack Developer**

- Built yard operation management platform using React, Next.js, GraphQL, Node.js, Express.js, Python, MySQL, Docker and AWS.
- Implemented real-time communication between yards and the server using **GraphQL** subscription.
- Contributed to building robust & scalable back-end **GraphQL** APIs.
- Maintained back-end code using Node.js/Express.js and Python/Django and collaborated with the product team to expand new features.
- Contributed to the in-house UI library to create reusable React components that saved over 20 hours of development time per week.
- Used skills: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Python, React, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, Django, MySQL, Docker, AWS, GitHub, Jira, Slack.

Voypost Feb 2015 - Nov 2017

### **Web Developer**

- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved functionality and speed using **JavaScript**, **Angular**, **PHP** and **Laravel**.
- · Helped many startups to successfully launch their MVPs.
- Developed user-friendly website, including optimized check-out page that increased user clicks, and subsequently customer purchased by 20% using **Angular**.
- Migrated legacy jQuery code to Angular version.
- Built semantic HTML pages using various CSS frameworks like Bootstrap, Material UI.
- Mocked static web pages using **HTML**, **CSS**, iQuery and **React**.
- Used skills: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, Angular, Laravel, Bootstrap, Material UI, Docker, AWS, Git, Jira, Slack, Figma, Photoshop.

### Skills (Years Of Experience)

• HTML / CSS (8) • React (6) • Node.js (4) • Bootstrap (4) MySQL (5) • React Native (3) • Express.js (4) • Material UI (4) JavaScript (7) PostgreSQL (3) TypeScript (5) Next.js (3) Nest.js (1) Tailwind CSS (3) MongoDB (3) Python (4) Vue.js (3) Django (3) • Chakra UI (2) AWS (3) • PHP (3) • Angular (2) • Laravel (3) • Styled Component (2) • Docker (3)